olympus-europa.com 2011-05-25

# Digital Camera, SLR, Cameras, Olympus, Endoscope, Endoscopy, Diagnostics, microscope, Microscopy, Medical Systems, Industrial Endoscopy, Voice Recorders, Binoculars, Business Solutions, Testing, Instruments, Equipement, Information, Olympus Europe

**1.  Introduction  
**We are Olympus Europa Holding GmbH, (Wendenstraße 14-18, 20097 Hamburg, Germany). All references to “we/our/us” refer to Olympus Europa Holding GmbH.    
“Personal information” is defined as any information which refers to you personally such as your name, e-mail address and postal address.   
Please read the following privacy policy to understand how we use your personal information after it has been collected by us.  Please read through this Privacy Policy before submitting any of your personal information to us.  You do not need to submit any of your personal information when browsing our website.   
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy at any time, please contact DataPrivacy[at]olympus-europa.com.  
This privacy policy may be updated from time to time. The date of the most recent revisions will appear on this page so please visit this privacy policy each time before you submit your personal information. 

**2.  When do we collect data?  
**We collect personal information from you when you do the following through our website:  
• register to order goods or services;   
• apply for a job with us or any of our subsidiaries (please see our separate Privacy Policy which asks for your consent before you can use our online application tool);  
• submit any other queries online.

**3.  What personal information do we collect from you?**  
We collect the following personal information from you when you register including your:  
• name;  
• postal address;  
• phone number;  
• email address;  
• any other personal information which is submitted with your job application (please see our separate Privacy Policy which needs your consent before you can use our online application tool).  
• any other personal information provided by you voluntarily

**4.  What do we do with your personal information?  
**When you give us any personal information as indicated above, we use your personal information to:  
• process your orders for goods and services;   
• correspond with you about your orders and provide you with information about the latest news or special offers which may be of interest to you unless you have opted to be excluded from these communications in a separate statement;    
• respond to your submitted queries and provide you with information about the latest news or special offers which may be of interest to you if you have opted to receive these communications in a separate statement;  
• process and correspond with you about your job application.

**5.  Who do we pass your personal information to?  
**We may share personal information collected via the website within our corporate group.  Otherwise, we will only disclose personal information to government bodies and law enforcement agencies, successors in title to our business and suppliers we engage to process data on our behalf. 

**6.  International transfers of personal information  
**On the basis that the Internet is a global environment, using the Internet to collect and process personal data necessarily involves the transmission of data across international boundaries. Therefore, by browsing the website and submitting personal information to us, you acknowledge our processing of your personal information on this basis. 

**7.  Cookies and Web Beacons from Yahoo!**  
When you view our websites we may store information on the hard drive of your computer in the form of a "cookie" (essentially a small text file or single GIF). Cookies allow us to tailor the websites to your interests and preferences. For example, a cookie might contain information about the web pages you have visited on the website, which could allow us to customise your next visit to the websites. However, cookies do not allow us access to the rest of your computer and we do not use them to collect personal information about you.

In order to analyse the success of our marketing campaigns, we also implement other technologies such as web beacons. We use third-party web beacons from Yahoo! to help analyze where visitors go and what they do while visiting our website. Yahoo! may also use anonymous information about your visits to this and other websites in order to improve its products and services and provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by Yahoo!, [click here](http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/us/yahoo/opt_out/targeting/details.html).

Most Internet browsers enable you to delete cookies or to receive a warning before a cookie is stored on your hard drive. Please refer to your browser instructions or help screen to learn more about how to do this. However, should you decide to disable any cookies we place on your computer you may not be able to use certain services or facilities on the website.

**8.  Linking to other websites**  
The website contains hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties.  These websites have their own privacy policies and we urge you to review them. They will govern the use of personal information you submit whilst visiting these websites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

**9.  IP Addresses**  
We study visitor trends since we are interested in the successful dissemination of information through the websites. Our server creates log files of information such as the Internet Protocol (IP) address from your network, what pages were explored and the length of your visit.  Analysis software is used to generate reports which help us to learn more about how we can enhance your experience with the websites.  This information is not used to develop a personal profile of you. The log files are regularly purged. An IP address is a number designated for your computer by your Internet service provider to provide access to the Internet.  Generally, an IP address will change every time your computer connects to the Internet.  However, if you have a broadband connection, it is possible that the IP address that we may gather may contain information that may be deemed identifiable.  This could occur due to the fact that by using certain broadband connections, your IP address would not change and could be associated with your personal computer. We may use your IP address to gather aggregate information on use. But we will only be able to identify you individually if we have the means of linking the IP address to you as a particular user. This usually requires access to additional information which we do not seek.

**10.  Your rights concerning your personal information  
**You have the right to request a copy of the personal information that we hold on you and to have any errors in that information corrected.  Please address your request to the data protection manager at DataPrivacy[at]olympus-europa.com. We will use reasonable efforts to supply, correct or delete personal information about you on our files.  
Furthermore, you have the right to object to the use of your personal information at any time. Please inform us either by using our contact address or the e-mail address stated above.

**January 5, 2010  
** **OLYMPUS Europe  
Data Privacy Officer  
**
